[Music]
earlier this year I was gifted a lovely
simple embroidery kit from my lovely
mother it seems that today is the day
for finishing projects I have been
meaning to finish I thought it
appropriate to try to finish this today
while I'm answering some of your
questions I asked on Instagram a while
ago what your questions were and quite a
few of the questions are ones that I've
already answered in previous Q&A videos
so I will link those down below
hopefully you can get a cup of tea and
enjoy this cozy little chat along with
me I appreciate your understanding this
week my video is a little bit shorter I
am very tired and so I am doing my best
to uh hold on my cat is a embroidery
thread Enthusiast so you will probably
see her joining me shortly I wanted to
begin uh several people asked how
married life is going now that we have
recently celebrated now now that we
recently got to a year and a half since
we got married I think we'll be 2 years
next uh may it is going very well I
think it is such an interesting process
learning how to coexist with another
individual learning not only how they
think and their lifestyle preferences
but also how to communicate effectively
Luke and I care a lot about our
communication to be very authentic and
straightforward I think that's one of
the most important things we've worked
on learning how to really connect with
another person and communicate in ways
that both of us understand can be
sometimes a very tiring process but if
you really keep going at it and there is
mutual respect and mutual willingness to
understand the other person's point of
view I think that it can be so
incredibly productive like every single
couple we have experienced challenges
together but we are getting through them
really well and so far it has been a
very rewarding experience and we are
also looking forward to raising a child
together as a very team effort one of
the reasons I fell in love with Luke is
that he is a very compassionate very
gentle soul he grounds me in the ways
that my artist self needs to be grounded
he also says that I compliment him with
my own creativity and my ability to
think in new ways we certainly
compliment each other and that has been
a really fruit full part of marriage as
for relationship advice I got quite a
few questions of that I by no means feel
like an expert Luke and I have been
together for about 5 years now and I
definitely don't consider myself an
expert at all however coming from a past
of experiencing some very abusive
relationships and moving through them I
would certainly say that the most
important thing is to feel safe and
respected around your partner for me
personally I won't speak for everyone
but for me personally if you don't feel
safe and you don't feel respected as a
person you don't feel like what you say
is respected or who you are is respected
I have never had a relationship be able
to function or Thrive if those things
are not met and that also means that I
need to provide that same respect and
kindness to the other person inevitably
any sort of relationship you will run
into differences of opinion and
sometimes friction and I think that if
you're able to navigate those things
without hurting the other person through
words and communication I think that is
that is a recipe for success but I also
know from my personal experience if you
want to have a respectful and
compassionate and kind relationship you
also have to believe that you are worthy
of receiving that sort of respect and
that kindness and demanding it and
accepting nothing less and that is that
is not easy to do I think that if you do
have that strong Foundation of mutual
respect and kindness I feel like a lot
of people can thrive in a relationship
even if they do have differences apart
from that I think something specifically
for Luke and I since we're two quite
introverted people one very helpful
thing for us is to do activities
together and spend quality time together
as well as spend quality time apart
there are many days where I am in my
artist studio working on a painting and
he may be working outside on a
woodworking project and we might spend
an afternoon like that and I think
that's a really positive thing I think
it's a really good thing for us to have
our independent interests but also share
a lot of mutual time together as well
another question I got quite often was
why did I decide to become a mother and
that one got me thinking for quite a
while um I completely respect and
understand that Parenthood is not for
everyone and that is completely okay for
me personally I have always found
children to be some of the most
fascinating people on the planet
especially when they're quite young they
are not self-conscious about being who
they are and expressing themselves and
seeing someone experience the world a
new to have all that magic and wonder
that I got to enjoy as I was a child
it's such a special gift to witness it
happening in a little human who is
growing up and trying to understand and
make sense of the world and find their
place in it I find that process to be
absolutely fascinating and that also
stems from my years as a preschool
teacher I find little humans to be so
interesting and I love talking with them
and spending time with them and I'm so
excited to see what type of adult they
will eventually become it is so
interesting there's so many
personalities out there so many ways of
seeing the world and I don't have any
strong opinion on who my child needs to
grow up to be I'm just so happy to see
them Thrive and find a way to navigate
this world and see who they become and
support them along the way another
question I got is what artists Inspire
my own art I'm going to completely
forget their names now so I am going to
list them here they are all incredible
artists that I take a lot of inspiration
from that do am amazing work however I
have to admit I had the gift of having
an absolutely incredible art teacher
growing up that always encouraged me to
look at other artists but to really
embrace my own desires and my own art
style and what I love to do and I think
that that's something that has extremely
benefited me it keeps me from comparing
and being too critical of myself it has
helped me embrace my art style and uh
really made me proud of the work I do
even though it might not be the best
work out there it is mine and it is
unique to me and that means so much I
don't do any sponsorships on my channel
and I also don't run ads in the middle
of my videos and so even though I am
happy with that decision I definitely
rely on my Etsy shop to make making
these videos worthwhile another question
that I got very often was if I will be
sharing my child online once the baby is
born and I definitely will not be doing
that you may see a little hand or a foot
or a shape of a child but I definitely
will not be sharing my child's face for
me personally that is what I'm
comfortable with I think with a baby so
young who has no idea what it means to
be online and to have their likeness
online and all that is um just not my
cup of tea uh for my own family it is a
personal choice for everyone and that is
just mine so I appreciate you
understanding I know not everyone will
be happy with that but I hope you
understand it is uh for my own sense of
privacy and so that I'm most comfortable
another question I got a couple times
was how do you deal with regret uh at
your life choices or not feeling happy
with where you are at at this time I
think every case is so individual but I
would say that every chapter of your
life can be a step forward and a step in
a New Direction I think one thing that
helped me um in regards to my life when
I was looking back on some very negative
relationships I have that left a lot of
very difficult memories to deal with was
that over time I started to come to
understand that even though those
experiences were painful they did partly
influence who I am now and I like to
think in a very positive way because
even though I would never want to go
back and experience those things again I
came to a point that I decided to not
let those people of my past those
decisions of the past hold any more
power over me
one helpful question I would always ask
myself in terms of my thoughts and how I
was feeling and how I was thinking about
memories or what my interior dialogue
was in general was are you helping or
hindering your journey forward and very
often a lot of my interior dialogue and
a lot of my focus on the past and
mistakes I made was only hindering my
journey because it was holding me back
from embracing a new beginning a new
life and forgiving myself accepting that
I did the best I could at the time with
the resources I had available to me and
that is the most I can expect from my
past self and that's the most I would
expect from anyone I need to hold myself
to the same standard of compassion and
kindness I hold other people and that
leads into my other question about
dealing with Stress and Anxiety and
anxious thoughts one phrase that really
helped me was Observe don't absorb and
that is easier said than done but when
you can slow slowly train yourself to
learn how to observe your feelings
accept them not try to judge them or
become angry at them over time through
practicing meditation and mindfulness
and focusing my thoughts in the present
in what I'm doing I found that slowly
working towards being very meditative
mindful learning how to focus my
thoughts on the present I learn to
practice observing my emotions not absor
absorbing my emotions I have learned
slowly to become someone who sees their
emotions honors them accepts them but is
not someone that is going to deeply
judge them become angry at themselves
for feeling them try really hard to
suppress them or run away from them
instead just be there and accept them
and do your best to stay in the present
and stay mindful I have found meditating
and journaling and really hyping
yourself up to believe in your ability
to change rewiring your brain is a very
real thing neuroplasticity is a real
thing all these incredible Studies have
shown us that we can change the way we
think and we do not have to always be a
slave to our anxiety we can make change
but we need to believe in our ability to
do it and that is the crucial first step
and then I found through my journey you
have to be patient because there is no
Quick Fix You need to dedicate yourself
to every day working on being present on
being in the moment to not let your
thoughts run away and fall down rabbit
hole and lead to a bunch more of anxiety
it takes time and it's going to take
many ups and downs it's a lifetime
journey and I can guarantee you it is so
fulfilling I understand this path is not
for everyone and not everyone is open to
this but for me personally embracing my
more spiritual side believing in
something bigger than myself it was so
crucial for me and I understand that's
not part of everyone's Journey but I
thought I'd share that it was part of
mine and it made a huge difference
another question I got which made me
giggle a little bit was how do you stay
so healthy and active because you seem
to be such a fit and athletic person and
I have to admit I I appreciate I
appreciate the question but I am not a
athletic person I am not gifted with
Athletics I am not a very physically uh
uh talented person when it comes to a
lot of of outdoor recreational
activities but yes I think this is a
good reminder that your your physical
appearance does not always necessarily
reflect your health and I think that's a
great thing to keep in
mind another question I get so often so
I just thought I'd answer it really
quickly is advice on homesteading I am
not a homesteader I think that is a very
common uh uh misconception I do have a
garden I Garden but I do not Homestead I
have several jobs I work full time I
just don't have the uh time and ability
to put into doing a project like that I
could not afford to take that time off
of work in order to fund a project like
that I know that there I'm sure many
people who are able to do something like
that and they do it quite creatively and
they find ways to save a lot of money um
but to have the ability to fund setting
all that up in the first place um is is
a huge Endeavor and it takes a lot of
time and energy energy and it's not
something that I can do at all I live in
a high desert region we have a lot of
concerns about water usage and water
rights to grow a large amount of food
and to have livestock and all that would
be um quite expensive in terms of water
I live in an HOA there are many
restrictions so I'm a boring slightly
unadventurous little cottage fairy who
just spends their time working and
puttering about their little garden and
their home and um I am not capable of
doing an enormous operation of that sort
I had quite a few questions asking how
I've changed since I've started this
Channel and I cannot even begin to say
I've changed so much as a person I
barely recognize who I was starting this
Channel and I think that's a really
wonderful thing it is such an incredibly
fruitful Journey I've been on and I
couldn't be more grateful for YouTube
for also encouraging me to go on that
Journey well then I have made very
little progress on this embroidery
project but but I think I'm going to go
ahead and listen to an Audi book and
work on this for a few more hours it is
so relaxing to work on projects like
these so I'm going to go ahead and do
that and I appreciate you so much for
being here thank you so much for
spending it cozy afternoon chatting with
me I hope you enjoyed this little video
I appreciate you being here thank you so
much I'm sending you so much love and
well wishes for a wonderful holiday
season for incredible New Year sending
you so many many blessings so much love
and I will see you very very soon
[Music]
goodbye